measuringflower.com 2018-11-01

# Privacy Policy - Measuring Flower

Your privacy is important to us, and maintaining your trust and confidence is one of our highest priorities. We respect your right to keep your personal information confidential and understand your desire to avoid unwanted solicitations. For this reason, please take a moment to look over our Privacy Policy.

This privacy policy sets out how Measuring Flower uses and protects any information that you give while using https://measuringflower.com (i.e. “Website”).

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

Measuring Flower may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from April 23, 2018. For questions or help, please [contact TJ](https://measuringflower.com/contact/).  

### What We Collect

**We may collect the following information:**

  * Contact information including name and email address.
  * Demographic information such as zip code, preferences, and interests.
  * Mailing address and phone number for delivery of products.
  * Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers.

#### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site, we collect the data shown in the comments form and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your Gravatar profile picture may be visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

#### Contact Forms

Information submitted to any of our contact forms is used solely for customer service purposes. No information is used for marketing purposes.

### What We Do with the Information We Gather

**We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:**

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers, or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, or mail. We may use the information to customize the website according to your interests.

### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

* * *

### Our Cookie Policy

In compliance with the European Union legislation, we inform you that our website will store some information about your preferences on your own computer inside a tiny file called a “cookie.”

A cookie is a small piece of data that a website asks your browser to store on your computer or mobile device. The cookie allows the website to “remember” your actions or preferences over time.

You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site and some services and functionalities may not work.

Most browsers support cookies, but users can set their browsers to decline them and can delete them whenever they like. A third-party website called [aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) has been setup to help you with instructions how you can do that on various browsers.

#### We use cookies to:

  * Identify you as a returning user and to count your visits in our traffic  
statistics analysis.
  * Remember your custom display preferences.
  * Suggest any recent searches you’ve made on our site.
  * Other usability features including tracking whether you’ve already given your consent to cookies.

Enabling cookies from our website is not strictly necessary for the website to work but it will provide you with a better browsing experience.

The cookie-related information is not used to identify you personally and the pattern data is fully under our control. These cookies are not used for any purpose other than those described here.

There may also be other types of cookies created after you’ve visited our website. We use Google Analytics, a popular web analytics service  
provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies to help us to analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie  
about your use of our website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our website, compiling reports on website activity and providing other  
services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google undertakes not to associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

When user ratings are enabled we store a WPRM_User_Voted_%recipe% cookie (with %recipe% the ID of the recipe) that contains the rating this user has given to a particular recipe. This cookie is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam.

#### Comments

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address, and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

When comment ratings are enabled we store the rating a user has given to a recipe along with the personal data WordPress core stores.

### Embedded Content

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

Measuring Flowere uses Google Analytics. This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

### IP Address

When recipe user ratings are enabled we store the IP address upon voting. This is used as (one of the) measures to prevent rating spam. Our cookies are stored for 30 days.

### Newsletter

Measuring Flowere has an email newsletter called the Leaflet. It is run using MadMimi. Your name and email are stored via MadMimi to send email newsletters and updates only; this information is never used for anything else and your information will never be sold or otherwise misused. You can learn more by reading MadMimi’s Privacy Policy.

### Affiliate Programs

We are monetary affiliates with various stores and websites including Trim Healthy Mama, Coupons.com, Redplum, and Amazon. Each of these track a cookie from our Website to theirs to ensure that we get paid a small portion of any sales for items we recommended to you (keep in mind that you pay nothing extra, we just get a little portion of their profits). This is necessary as this is how we keep our website up and running without any membership fees.

### Recipe Submission

With the Recipe Submission feature personal data can be collected, depending on the fields that were added to the form. This can include the user email and name. When using the reCAPTCHA feature you will be agreeing to their terms of use and privacy policy. User submitted data is stored indefinitely in the local database.

### Third Party Advertising

We may have third-party advertising companies serving ads to you when you visit our website. These companies may store information about your visits to our website and to other websites in order to provide you with relevant advertisements about goods and services.

These companies may employ cookies and other identifiers to gather information which measures advertising effectiveness. The information is generally not personally identifiable unless, for example, you provide personally identifiable information to them through an ad or an e-mail message.

#### Information Gathered by Third Party Advertisers

Cookies enable advertisers to learn about what ads you see, what ads you click, and other actions you take on our site and other sites. This allows advertisers to provide you with more useful and relevant ads. For example, if they know what ads you are shown while visiting our site, they can be careful not to show you the same ones repeatedly. They do not associate your interaction with unaffiliated sites with your identity in providing you with interest-based ads.

We do not provide any personal information to advertisers or to third party sites. Advertisers and other third-parties (including the ad networks, ad-serving companies, and other service providers they may use) may assume that users who interact with or click on a personalized ad or content are part of the group that the ad or content is directed towards (for example, readers in the Pacific Northwest who read certain types of articles). Also, some third-party cookies may provide them with information about you (such as the sites where you have been shown ads or demographic information) from offline and online sources that they may use to provide you more relevant and useful advertising.

If you would like to learn more about what options you have about limiting the gathering of information by third-party ad networks, you can consult the website of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

You can opt out of participating in interest-based advertising networks but opting out does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the companies from which you opted out will no longer customize ads based on your interests and web usage patterns using cookie-based technology.

#### Type and Purpose of Collection

We collect information at various points in the Website to facilitate its use by our customers. Non-Personal Information: Upon accessing the Website, certain non-personal information will be automatically collected without your knowledge or consent, such as your IP address, location data (which is anonymous) and the referring website (“Non-Personal Information”). We use Non-Personal Information to examine our traffic and to view how our customers use the Website. This type of information will not allow you to be personally identified. For example, we use ”cookies”, which contains only certain statistical information. You can instruct your computer to inform you whenever a cookie is being sent, or you can disallow cookies through your web browser. If you do choose to disallow cookies, your experience on the  
Website may be diminished, or your ability to choose some of the options on the Website may be limited.

* * *

### Sharing Information

We will not sell, rent or disclose to outside parties the information we collect, save and except that we may share the collected information with other parties as follows:

  * Affiliated Service Providers: We have agreements with various affiliated service providers to facilitate the functioning of the Website, with whom we may share the information we have collected. For example, we may share your credit card information with the credit card service provider to process your purchase. All administrative service providers that we use are required to have the same level of privacy protection as we have, and therefore we expect that your information will be handled with the same level of care that we employ. Additionally, for example, we may use analytic or marketing services such as Google Analytics, Google Adsense, Taboola, or RevContent, to which collection you hereby unconditionally consent.
  * Where required by law: We may share the collected information where required by law, specifically in response to a demand from government authorities where such demand meets the legal requirements.
  * Statistical Analysis: We may share Non-Personal Information and aggregated information with third parties, including but not limited to for advertising or marketing purposes. No Personal Information will be shared in this manner.
  * Transactions: In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition, or in any other situation where Personal Information may be disclosed or transferred as one of our business assets.

* * *

### Choices and How To Opt Out Of Interest-Based Advertising

  * Opting Out of Interest-Based Advertising Services This website is a member of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) (NAI) and adheres to the NAI Codes of Conduct as described on the NAI website. This website also adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) Self-Regulatory Principles. For a description of the DAA Program, please visit the [DAA website](http://digitaladvertisingalliance.org/). As described above, this website may use or transfer Device Data that it directly collects or that it receives from this website’s Customers, who may use cookies or non-cookie technologies, to enable advertising that is more tailored to Consumers’ inferred interests, preferences, and locations. This practice is known as interest-based advertising.
  * Opting Out of Interest-Based Advertising by Third Parties. This website may permit third parties to collect information on its Site and combine that information with other information collected on non-affiliated websites or applications over time. These third parties may use technologies, including cookies and web beacons, to collect information about Consumers’ or Customers’ use of the Site in order to analyze, report on, or customize content or advertising on the this website or on other sites, or to help us operate and improve the Site. To find out more about interest-based advertising in the web environment, and how to opt-out of information collection for this purpose by companies that participate in the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, visit [NAI’s opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/) or [DAA’s Consumer Choice Page](http://optout.aboutads.info/).data is stored indefinitely in the local database.
